A few years ago, I began to observe something in my own behavior that made me a bit uncomfortable. And that was that, from the moment that I woke up to the end of the day, my life was
And so I sat there in bed watching various cooking videos on Instagram and bouncing
And so the thing that I focused then on, in addition to the omelet in the pan, was the iPad that was right next to the oven, and then it was time to do some work.
All the while this little devil on my wrist was tapping and beeping and blooping and distracting me as I was trying to get important stuff done. But there was one particular offender out of all of these different devices that I wasted
And so I decided to, essentially, for all intents and purposes, get rid of the thing for
to listen to music, to listen to podcasts, and I observed what happened during this time. It took about a week to adjust downward into a new lower level of stimulation. But once I did, I noticed that three curious things began to happen.
We think about the past, we think about the present, and we think about the future. But we think about the past less than we might think, only about 12% of the time, and often the time we're recalling ideas in these thought-wandering episodes. But the present, which is a much more productive place to wander, we wander to think about
And so this is, you know, as simple as you're typing up an email, and you can't find a
the solution hits you because your mind had a chance to approach it and prod at that
Our mind's wander to think about the future more than the past and the present combined. Whenever our mind is wandering, we think about the future 48% of the time. This is why when we're taking a shower, we plan out our entire day, even though it hasn't
This is called our mind's prospective bias, and it occurs when our mind wanders. If you're good with math, or maths, I should say, not in Canada anymore, these numbers
doesn't have an idea inside of it that is rooted in time. But whatever it is for you that lets your mind wander, something that's simple, something
Could be simple, if you're at work, walking from one room to another in the office. Very simple change, but if you don't use your phone during that walk, your mind will
on, it will wander to the ideas that are circulating and it will make you more creative in this
It could be something as simple as waiting in line and just waiting in line, it could be getting a massage, whatever it is that lets your mind, I love this picture so much.
you and you're always incubating things and so capture them so you can act upon them later. But I think after doing this deep dive into the research, we need to make two fundamental shifts with regard to how we think about our attention.
You know, there's all this talk about hustling, I'm an anti-hustler, I'm one of the laziest
The second shift, we like to think of distraction as the enemy of focus. It is not, it is a symptom of why we find it difficult to focus, which is the fact
It's a two-week challenge, but it's a challenge to make your mind a bit less stimulated and simply notice what happens to your attention, how many ideas do you get, how does your focus
There are so many great features on phones, on devices that let us eliminate a lot of the
from the internet completely from 8 p.m. to 8 a.m. My fiance and I, we have a weekly disconnection ritual, a technology Sabbath every Sunday, so we can disconnect from the digital world and reconnect with the physical world, the real
But rediscover boredom, just for a few minutes, lay on the couch and where does your mind go
You'll find some remarkably fruitful things in that attentional zone. If there's one thing that I have found to be true, after doing this deep dive into this world on how we focus, it's that the state of our attention is what determines the
If we're distracted in each moment, those moments of distraction and overstimulation build up and accumulate to create a life that feels more distracted and overwhelming like we
But when we become less stimulated, when we make our mind more calm, we get the benefits of added productivity and focus and ideas and creativity, but we also live a better life